Finding Aid for the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection LSC.0100
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Author Identified
  - Wallace, Henry A. (Box 192, Folder 9-10)
    - Articles., n.d. (Box 192, Folder 10)
      Open letter to Premier Stalin (Los Angeles Progressive Party), n.d. newspaper articles re Wallace.
  - Wadsworth, James T., To Lucia A. Robbins, Stockton, California. 1851-1852 3 letters. A.L.S. (Box 10)
    Gift of Hazel S. Vaughan, April, 1954.
    Letters to his niece in Plymouth, Massachusetts, describing his experiences in California.
  - Waite, Morrison Remick, 1816-1888. To Walter L. Gresham, Washington. 1875 October 9 1 p. engraved letter signed. (Box 16)
    Letter signed and annotated by Waite, Chief Justice of the United States, appointing Oliver B. Siddell as Register in Bankruptcy for the district of Indiana. Also includes an autographed card.
  - Wales, George Edward, 1792-1860. To [Samuel Lewis Southard], Secretary of the Navy, Washington. 1827 March 2 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 10)
    Requesting appointment as midshipman for Daniel Parsons. Also signed by Henry Howard Ross.
  - Walker, Emery, 1851-1933. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph, typescript. (Box 12)
  - Walker, Richard Frederick, 1831-, papers. 1865-1904 20 items. (Box 32)
    Letters and papers of Richard F. Walker of Virginia, who held the rank of Major in the Confederate Army. Most of the papers related to his efforts to secure political appointments. A biographical sketch is included.
  - Waln, Robert, 1765-1836. To John Nicholson. 1794 Nov 10 Holograph signed. 2 p. (Box 4)
  - Wardell, Daniel, 1701-1878. To Francis Preston Blair, Mannsville, New York [?]. 1833 July 9 (Box 31)
  - Wardwell, Representative from New York, writes to assure Blair that General Dunian [?] voted for Blair's appointment as government printer. 2 pp. Holograph signed. (Box 31)
  - Warfield, Helen M. (Box 195, 198)
    - Letters to her mother., 1918-1919.; (17 letters). (Box 198, Folder 4)
      re visit to Australia (1st letter missing 1st page). 1 hand drawn map of Australia.
    - Diary., 1918-1919.; (Loose-leaf). (Box 195, Folder 3)
      With photographs, clippings, etc., for September 21, 1918-May 4, 1919 re Pacific travels.
  - Warfield, Henry R. To Hezekiah Niles, Annapolis, Maryland. 1835 January 18 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    An inquiry to the editor of Niles' Register concerning an account of the burning of the brig, "Peggy Stewart," during the Revolution.
  - Warren, Althea. Letter to Rabbi Maxwell H. Dubin., 1945. (Box 201, Folder 4)
    Gift of Rabbi Maxwell H. Dubin.
  - Warren, Joseph, 1829-1876. Correspondence. 1870-1872 13 letters. (Box 32)
    Letters to John Thompson Hoffman, Governor of New York, concerning political affairs in New York and particularly in the City of Buffalo. In 1870, Warren was chosen president of the New York Press Association. He was also editor of the Buffalo Courier and a Park Commissioner of the City of Buffalo.
  - Warren, Mrs. Stafford, ed. Municipal Research newsletter (Rochester, New York)., 1936-1946.; (Bound). (Box 187, Folder 3)
    Contains numbers 1 thru 114.
  - Wasson, David Atwood, 1823-1887. Correspondence to Franklin Benjamin Sanborn. 1857-1868 30 items. Holograph. (Box 32)
    Wasson discusses his writings on African Americans, as well as his poetry. There are mentions of Emerson, Thoreau, and Tennyson.
  - Watmough, John Goddard, 1793-1861. To H[ezekiah] Niles. 1834 October 13 2 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning a local election campaign (Md.?). Watson, John E. To Mr. Eakin, Germantown, Pennsylvania. 1833 January 9 2 pp. Holograph signed.
  - Watson, George. Letters to "Dear brother & sister.", 1862.; (3 items). (Box 194, Folder 5)
    Posted Grafton, Virginia, dated February and March 2, 1862, and 1 pay voucher to Regiment sutter (82d Ohio Infantry).
  - Waugh, Arthur, 1866-1943. Correspondence. 1931 1 folder. (Box 7)
    Removed from: Waugh, Arthur. One Man's Road. London, 1931.
    England. 2 holograph, signed, to Dr. George C. Williamson. 1 copy of letter to Waugh, unsigned (from Dr. George C. Williamson?).
  - Weaver, Raymond Melbourne, 1888-1948. Correspondence. 1921-1925 1 folder. (Box 18)
    Gift: John A Burrell, 1957.
    Correspondence of Weaver, regarding the first collected edition of Melville's works (Constable 1922-1924) with John Freeman, Michael Sadleir, Havelock Ellis, and James Barrie's secretary. Also includes the prelude to the Constable Edition of Melville, by Philip Durham. HLQ, 1958 May.
  - Webb, Charles Henry, 1834-1904. Publishers agreement and receipt signed between Webb and publisher E. Bliss, Jr. 1874 December 1 2 p. Holograph. (Box 13)
  - Webb, Dorothy Haldeman. Harry Marston Haldeman, April 5, 1871-March 10, 1930., 1976.; (Typescript). (Box 188, Folder 1)
  - Webb, James Watson, 1802-1884. Correspondence. 1839-1876 5 letters. (Box 32)
    Includes biographical sketches.
  - Wellford, Bev. R. Correspondence. 1827 2 pieces. (Box 16)
    Letter from Wellford to S[amuel] L[ewis] Southard, Secretary of the Navy, Fredericksburg, Maryland, 1827 February 11, concerning a charge against Southard as a critic of Andrew Jackson's actions at the Battle of New Orleans, and mentioning Samuel Houston's indignation. A letter from William M. Blackford, witness to Southard's remarks, denying any criticism, and mentioning financial affairs of James Monroe, 1827
  - Werfel, Franz, 1890-1945. "Der Dirigent" - poem., n.d.; (1 item, 1p. [holograph, signed, in German]). (Box 284, Folder 10)
    Note from gerald Olds (Gifts).
  - Weston, Agnes. Newspaper clippings., n.d.; (1 item, 2pp.). (Box 282, Folder 5)
    re HRH King Edward VII's recognition of Weston's founding of the Soldier's and Sailor's Home.
  - Wheeler, William, Almon, 1819-1887. To Reverend Dr. Taylor, Washington. 1879 February 24 2 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
  - White, Campbell Patrick, 1787-1859. Correspondence. 1833-1853. 4 pieces. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    White, Representative from New York, writes to Francis Preston Blair concerning the latter's election as printer, and to several collectors of customs, making recommendations for appointments.
  - Whyte-Melville, George John, 1821-1878. Correspondence, signed to various persons. 16 items. Holograph. (Box 29)
    2 letters toJohn William Parker, undated. 3 letters to Frederic Chapman, undated.
  - Wickes, George. Miscellaneous material relating to Henry Miller., n.d.; (4 items, 4pp. [holograph] and [typescript]). (Box 289, Folder 8)
    Letter (27 April, n.y.), manuscript of Table of Contents, and list of Miller's books.
    Found in Osborn correspondence.
    Card under H. Miller.
  - Widney, Joseph Pomeroy (Box 191, Folder 2-4)
    - Correspondence., 1931-1940. (Box 191, Folder 2)
    - Photographs., n.d. (Box 191, Folder 3)
    - Magazine articles and published materials., 1895 & 1936-38. (Box 191, Folder 4)
      Articles from University Courier & Los Angeles Times Sunday magazine and various publications.
  - Wight, Frederick Stallknecht, 1902-1986. Verge of glory. Los Angeles. Circa 1955 3 items. (Box 22)
    Includes a typescript manuscript with irregular pagination and a typescript manuscript with 412 leaves. Also included galley proofs of 104 sheets. All are with holograph corrections. The manuscript is a novel about Amedeo Modigliani, published by Harcourt, New York, 1956.
  - Wilder, Thornton. Manuscript, essay to be read on radio., c. 1950.; (1 item, 8pp. [holograph]). (Box 281, Folder 10)
    re American Veterans Committee.
    Gift of Nathen and Dorothy Horowitz.
  - Wilkie, Sir David, 1785-1841. Correspondence to Thomas Phillips. 1836 June 7 1 item. Holograph. (Box 17)
  - Willford, Charles. Letter to Lawrence Clark Powell., 1959. (Box 192, Folder 24)
    re donation of three books and a manuscript.
  - Williams, Lewis, 1786-1842. To Hezekiah Niles, Washington. 1832 June 6 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Requesting information concerning a letter on Nullification, a movement which Williams, a Congressman from North Carolina, terms "an abominable and wicked heresy ... gaining ground in the South" and which he believes to be of British origin.
  - Williams, Manly R. Correspondence and photographs of the Williams family. Circa 1880-1900 13 pieces. (Box 28)
  - Willis, Nathaniel Parker, 1806-1867. Signed correspondence. v.p., v.d. not in box 12/86 dl. 4 items. Holograph. (Box 7)
    1 letter to Andrew Jackson Downing, n.d. 1 letter to Horatio Hastings Weld, n.d. 1 letter to Joseph Grinnel, 1864 July 6. 1 letter to "Lynchie," 1853 February 12.
  - Willson, Meredith, 1902-1984. Eggs I have laid. Circa 1955 6 p. l., 171 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 27)
    Gift of author, November, 1955.
    Published by Holt, New York, 1955.
  - Wilson, Mrs. Augusta Jane (Evans), 1835-1909. Letter to Mrs. Caro Smith Senour, Mobile. February? 1 p. dictated. (Box 20)
    Thanks for books on cat. "Feeble health and impaired vision combine to deprive me of the pleasures of travel."
  - Wilson, John, 1785-1854. Correspondence, signed, to various persons. 3 items. Holograph. (Box 29)
    1 letter to Alaric Alexander Watts, 1826 October 7.
  - Wilson, Thomas Woodrow, United States president, 1865-1924. Correspondence. 1911, 1918 2 pieces. (Box 7)
    Letter to Robert E. Rinehart, dated 1911 April 7. Letter to Mrs. Archibald Hopkins, dated 1918 February 1.
  - Wingfield, Lewis Strange, 1842-1891. Signed correspondence. v.p., v.d. 3 items. Holograph. (Box 6)
  - Wolfe, Thomas, 1900-1938. Correspondence. 1930, 1935 2 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 7)
    1 letter to Richard Aldington, Paris, 1930 September 28. 8 pages, holograph. 1 letter to Lawrence Clark Powell, New York, New York, 1935 July 16. 1 page, typescript, signed.
  - Wood, Samuel Edgerton. The California State Commission of immigration and housing: a study of administrative organization and the growth of function, Berkeley. iii, 228 leaves. typescript draft with holograph corrections. (Box 8)
    Unpublished?
  - Woodhouse, John. Various publications written and edited by John Woodhouse., 1967-1978. (Box 191, Folder 8)
  - Woody, Mary, comp. Commonplace book. n.p. circa 1800 16 p. 32 x 32 centimeters. Holograph manuscript in ink. (Box 7)
    Gift of Mrs. Thomas B. Williamson, 1952 February 7.
    Pages and portions of pages are missing from this early American commonplace book. Includes "The true account of Nayomy Wise," American ballad. Bound in limp linen. Another copy (17 photographic reproductions). See also: Collection Film 100 box 19 for another copy: numbers 1 and 2. 2 reels. 35 millimeter negative microfilm.
  - Wordsworth, William, 1779-1850. Correspondence to John Jebb, Bishop of Limerick, Ardfert, and Aghadoe. 1833 January 28 1 item. Holograph. (Box 17)
  - Workman, Boyle. City that grew. 1935 January-March 1 folder. Clippings. (Box 11)
    Gift: J. Gregg Layne, 1952 May 20.
    Complete set of publication of City that grew, by Los Angeles Herald-Express.
  - Wright, Helen. Palomar, the world's largest telescope. 1952 194 p. Typescript. (Box 13)
    Gift: Author.
    Published by Macmillan, 1952.
  - Wysor, William Wirt, 1848-1897. Correspondence to sister, Cadiz. 1844 December 4 1 p. glossy photoprint. (Box 20)
    Gift of Mrs. Frank J. Klingberg. Carson, Josephine, 1919-. Drives my green age. Typescript and galley proofs. Layout dummy. Circa 1957 215 pages. 2 pieces.
    Published by Harper, 1957.
  - Florence Yoch Correspondence, 1956-1967.
    Collection consists of letters from friends and relatives to landscape architect Florence Yoch, two photographs, and one typescript draft of a letter from Yoch. Most of the letters are not dated. Many of the letters are from Anne Trevithick, wife of New Zealand architect Cecil Trevithick. Photographs include a group picture of a tour group (1967) and a snapshot of the Trevithicks.
  - Young, La Monte (Collection of Pamphlets, Programs and Correspondence), 1965-1975.; (1 box, 10 items).
    Selected writings, catalogs, lectures and correspondence relating to musical programs and other performance events of La Monte Young and Marian Zazeela.
  - Yule, Sir Henry, 1820-1889. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 19)
  - Zangwill, Israel, 1864-1926. The baron of Offenbach: a cabbalistic romance. (Box 10)
    Unpublished. The typescript from which this Xerox copy was made belongs to the British Museum Library. Unbound.
    n.p., n.d. 132 leaves. 30 centimeters. Xerox copy of a transcript.
  - Zangwill, Israel, 1864-1926. Dreamers of the ghetto in congress. [London, Unwin Brothers, Gresham Press, 1897]. 1897 3 sheets. 55 by 18.5 centimeters. Proof sheets with holograph corrections in ink. (Box 10)
    Ex libris: Kenneth Mackenna [Mielziner].
    An article published in "Cosmopolis," October, 1897. Presented by the author to Jo Mielziner. A letter, 1902 March 29, from Zangwill to Leo Mielziner, originally with this manuscript, is now filed with the Zangwill letters to Mr. and Mrs. Leo Mielziner.
  - Zangwill, Israel, 1864-1926. Letters and ephemera. 1892-1957 4 folders. (Box 10)
    Folder 1: 12 letters, 1894-1921, to Leo and Ella Mielziner. 41 letters, 1892-1926, to various people. Folder 2: Clippings and ephemera by and about Zangwill. Folder 3: Bibliographical notes by Ella Mielziner about her collection of Zangwill's works. Folder 4. Correspondence of Ella Mielziner with dealers and others about her Zangwill collection.
  - Zangwill, Israel, 1864-1926. When I am dead. n.p. 1926 2 sheets. 62.5 by 11.5 centimeters. Galley proofs with corrections in ink. (Box 10)
    Published in the "Outlook," 1926 August 11, (volume 42, page 502-503).
  - Zeitlin, Jake, 1902-. "Building a Book Collection" - (speech?) audio recording - Anaheim Public Library., 1968 6 June.; (1 reel-to-reel tape). (Box 288, Folder 1)
    Card under Zeitlin, Jake.
  - Zoritch, George. Photographs., n.d.; (87 items). (Box 284, Folder 5)
    87 photographs (3 color), 27 signed, most with captions on back. Family, portraits and performances.
    Gift of George Zoritch.
  - Zuber, Augusta, M.D. Documents., 1915-1931. (Box 201, Folder 9)
    Health and development certificate (California) and 12 dues cards from California Board of Medical Examiner.
    Gift of Don Gilstrap.